# 三种不同的醋  口感是不一样的
Three different kinds of vinegar. They taste differently
# 味道出来了
The scent has come out
# 这个老醋汁是我干了这么多年凉菜
This vinegar sauce is from my years of experience of making cold dishes
# 自己的一个心得体会
My own experience and understanding
# 我这胃已经炸开了
It's exploding in my stomach
# 喝酒的小菜儿 老醋花生
A drunk food, "Lao Cu Hua Sheng" ("peanuts in aged vinegar")
# 今天要用的花生是这种小粒的花生
# 注：不太确定“小粒花生”这样译对不对，请检查
Today we're gonna use small-seed peanuts
# 第一步得把这花生
First of all
# 咱们得先轻轻洗一下
We need to rinse the peanuts for a bit
# 为了让它下油锅以后
So that when deep frying
# 不至于那么快就变颜色
Their color doesn't change so quickly
# 炸花生的时候最好用花生油
It's best to fry peanuts in peanut oil
# 我师父都给我倒好了 花生油香啊
- My master has poured it out already
- Peanut oil smells great
# 凉锅凉油凉花生下锅
Cold peanuts into cold wok and cold oil
# 怎么炸到合适呢 咱们在里边扔瓣儿蒜
How do we know when they are fried well? We put a clove of garlic
# 什么时候这个蒜表面金黄了熟透了
When the garlic has turned golden brown and fully cooked
# 这个花生也就基本上差不多了
The peanuts should also be good enough
# 小火 在这给我们网友提示一下
- Low heat
- Here's a tip for our friends
# 你看这花生下去以后它是冒大泡的
As you see, when we put the peanuts in, the bubbles are large
# 等我们越炸的时候
As we fry longer and longer
# 这油越来越变成小泡
The bubbles become smaller
# 就说明这个水分少了
It means there's less water left
# 这个不是时间的事
This is not about the time
# 是要把水分要炸干 这声音有点脆了啊
- It's about getting rid of the water completely
- It sounds a bit crunchy already
# 您看这个蒜已经金黄了
As you see, the garlic has turned golden brown
# 我觉得应该可以捞了
I think we can take them out
# 然后咱们这盘子上放张吸油纸
Then we put a piece of oil-absorbing paper on this tray
# 把这油吸一下
To absorb the oil
# 咱们把它摊在盘子里边 吸油 晾凉
Let them rest in the tray, oil absorbed and cooled
# 然后这儿还有一个小关键点
And then we have a key step
# 咱们滴两滴白酒
We spray a few drops of baijiu liquor
# 可以保持这花生米酥脆
It helps keeping the peanuts crunchy
# 咱们把花生拌匀 一定晾凉吹干
Let's mix the peanuts well. Must be cooled and fan-dried
# 下一步咱们兑一个老醋汁
Next, we prepare a "aged vinegar sauce"
# 这个老醋汁是我干了这么多年凉菜
This vinegar sauce is from my years of experience of making cold dishes
# 自己的一个心得体会
My own experience and understanding
# 这一共用了三种醋
We have three kinds of vinegar here
# 陈醋 香醋 还有清香米醋
"Chencu" aged vinegar, "Xiangcu" vinegar, and rice vinegar
# 咱们先在这里边放 糖
First put in some sugar
# 这糖要多少 糖有一百克
- How much sugar?
- 100 g of sugar
# 咱们再来点盐 咱们适量
Then we add some salt to taste
# 这陈醋可以二百克
We can put up to 200 g of "Chencu" vinegar
# 我在这儿就不倒那么多了
This time we don't need that much
# 咱们香醋 就是镇江香醋
"Xiangcu" vinegar, aka Zhenjiang vinegar
# 刚才咱们（陈醋）倒了有一百克
We just added about 100 g of "Chencu" vinegar
# 咱们这香醋有六十克就可以了
For "Xiangcu" vinegar, 60 g is enough
# 这清香米醋有二十克 酸味稳定
20 g of rice vinegar, with a stable sourness
# 三种不同的醋口感是不一样的
Three different kinds of vinegar. They taste differently
# 酸度也不一样
Their acidities are different, too
# 然后咱们再滴一点香油
Then add a few drops of sesame oil
# 这醋汁基本就调好了
Now the vinegar sauce should be done
# 大爷 葱头 尖椒
- Da Ye!
- Shallots, and chili peppers
# 花生也差不多了
The peanuts should also be good now
# 酥脆 这火候拿捏的准确
Crunchy! Cooked to the right degree accurately!
# 行了别老掂了再掂都得给掂碎了
Alright, you can stop tossing. You'll break them if you keep tossing
# 要听这声音啊
We need to hear the sound
# 来咱们把这汁浇到里边 拌一下
Now let's pour the sauce in, and mix it
# 齐了
Finished
# 你看看这味道出来了
The scent has come out
# 好 照相
Good, take a picture
# 带汁儿的有味儿的 小菜大智慧
The sauce and the flavor. Wisdom hidden in a tiny dish
# 别小看小菜
Don't look down upon tiny dishes
# 脆吗 那当然脆了
- Is it crunchy?
- Crunchy, of course
# 现在我这胃已经炸开了
It feels extraordinary!
# 小菜 也要做的专业
Even a tiny dish should still be done in the professional way
# 三种醋的这种调和
The mixing of the three vinegars
# 到嘴里这种清脆
The crunchiness in the mouth
# 这个真好
This is so good
# 这网友子淞问
Our audience Zisong asks
# 做宫保鸡丁的时候
When making Kung Pao Chicken
# 滑油和不滑油有什么区别
What's the difference between "Hua You" and not "Hua You"?
("Hua You": Parcook the ingredient by slightly frying in oil)
# 然后还有有人做的时候
And some people add chili powder
# 有的时候在最后加辣椒油
While some others add chili oil when finishing
# 这个味道上又有什么区别
What are the different flavors?
# 滑油
Hua You
# 与不滑油
Or not Hua You
# 两种烹调方法
Two different methods
# 过去呢
In the past
# 就是讲究卧油煸炒
We want dry stir frying in the "Wo You" style
("Wo You": All cooking done continuously without parcooking)
# 但是这个煸炒加辣椒面
However, if you add chili powder when dry stir frying
# 它炒出的东西更香
The food is more fragrant
# 但是如果说要滑油的话
If you Hua You instead
# 可能要出菜形式
The presence of the dish is probably
# 要比他要整齐
Neater than the other method
# 是吧
Yeah
# 而且油滑的要比那个煸炒要有把握
And Hua You is easier to master than dry stir frying
# 还要嫩
It's also more tender
# 加辣椒面是过去这些老的 大的饭店
Adding chili powder is what the old, big restaurants do in the past
# 当时北京饭店和前门饭店
Like Beijing Hotel and Qianmen Hotel
# 是最火的
The most popular ones at that time
# 因为那是十大饭店
Because they are among the top ten restaurants
# 十大饭店是吧
Top ten restaurants, are they?
# 而且那些那些老师傅
And all those experienced chefs
# 都是
They were like
# 国家给调过来
The government assigned them there
# 原籍四川的
They are originally from Sichuan
# 他们也是继承了老一辈的
They also inherited the traditional techniques
# 这种传统技法
from the past generation
# 煸完了之后
After dry stir frying
# 加上辣椒面
Add chili powder
# 加辣椒面
# 它有一种辣椒的那种清香味
It has the refreshing fragrance of chili peppers
# 和鸡丁揉在一块
Together with chicken dice
# 那种香气更浓一些
The fragrance is even stronger
# 但是它不好在哪呢
However, what's the down side?
# 这煸辣椒面
To dry fry chili powder
# 和卧油煸炒
and to dry stir fry in the Wo You style
# 这需要你有一定的功夫了
You have to be skillful enough
# 如果说
In case
# 您的功夫差点
You are not that skillful
# 可能是辣椒面 可能就煸糊了
You'll probably burn the chili powder
# 或者鸡丁的出来
Or when cooking the chicken dice
# 掌握不好的油温的
If you use the wrong oil temperature
# 他就不嫩了
It's not tender any more
# 这需要有一定的难度
This is somewhat difficult
# 但是滑炒相对来讲就难度
Comparatively, the difficulty of Hua You
# 稍微低一点是吧
It's a bit lower
# 最后放辣椒油的话
How about finishing with chili oil?
# 辣椒油是现代的产物
Chili oil is a modern product
# 不是过去的
Not a traditional one
# 它以胡辣 小荔枝为口的
# 注：这里说的应该是宫保鸡丁口味改良史。考虑到这部分是严肃的知识讲解，就帮他们注明了
The traditional flavors (of Kung Pao Chicken) was mostly "Hu La" and "Xiao Li Zhi"
# 这种口味是吧
Those flavors, right?
# 然后改成现在有点大甜酸了
And now it has become kind of a strong sweet and sour flavor
# 大甜酸之后
After becoming sweet and sour
# 他就炼红油
They use chili oil
# 炼红油第一省事
First of all, chili oil is convenient
# 第二个颜色漂亮
Second, the color looks pretty
# 是现代版的这种产物
That's a modern product
# 吃起来的味道还是有些 有些区别
When you eat it, the taste is still a bit different
# 要辣干辣的那种
# （不会译...）
Different in their types of spiciness
# 他们在制作红油的时候
And when they make chili oil
# 也加了一些特殊的香料
They also add some special spices
# 追求的是颜色
Their goal is the color
# 这就是不一样
That's so different
# 两位拥有60多万赞的人就是不一样
With over 600k likes, you two look so different
# 这气色
Looking great!
# 别唱了大爷
Stop singing, Da Ye
# 开始
Start
# 对不起啊
Sorry
# 等一下
Wait a minute
# 我录上了吗
Am I recording
# 您自己都不在线上
You are not even online yourself
# 线下的你
You are offline